Register of the Lawrence Dennis Papers, 1921-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
Lawrence Dennis Papers,
1921-1975
84036
Dennis, Lawrence, 1893-
24 manuscript boxes (10 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence and writings, relating to fascist and isolationist movements in the U.S., and to American politics and foreign policy. Includes copies of the newsletters edited by L. Dennis, and subscription records.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Fascism--United States.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; United States--Neutrality.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; Journalists.
Biographical Note
1893, Dec. 25 Born, Atlanta, Georgia
1915-1917 Served at Plattsburg, commissioned 2nd Lt. U.S. Army, Aug. 1917
1918-1919 Served with American Expeditionary Force
1921-1927 U.S. Department of State. Posts in Haiti, Romania, Honduras (1925) and Nicaragua (1926-1927)
1927-1930 Employed by J. & W. Seligman & Co., bankers, New York City
1932 Author, Is Capitalism Doomed?
1936 Author, The Coming American Fascism
1936-1939 Employed by E.A. Pierce & Co., brokers, New York City
1939-1942 Editor and publisher of The Weekly Foreign Letter
1940 Author, The Dynamics of War and Revolution
1944-1947 Tried for sedition, 1944; case dismissed, 1947
1946 Author (with Maximilian J. St. George), A Trial on Trial
1946-1972 Editor and publisher of The Appeal to Reason
1969 Author, Operational Thinking for Survival
1977, Aug. 20 Died, Spring Valley, New York
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1915-1973. (Box Box 1)
  Biographical sketches, clippings, interviews, lecture notices, foreign service materials, copies of military service materials, and miscellany, relating to the life of Lawrence Dennis, arranged alphabetically by form.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1930-1977. (Box Boxes 1-5)
  Significant correspondence of Lawrence Dennis, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes a few letters neither to nor from Lawrence Dennis.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1931-1975. (Box Boxes 6-9)
  Drafts, manuscript copies, proofs, radio transcripts, other typed and printed copies of speeches and writings by Lawrence Dennis, arranged chronologically.
- WEEKLY FOREIGN LETTER, 1938-1942. (Box Boxes 10-11)
  Numbers 1-206 (#7, #56, #83 missing) of weekly newsletter produced by Lawrence Dennis, arranged chronologically. Dennis began contributing with the issue of 1939 Feb. 17.
- APPEAL TO REASON, 1946-1972. (Box Boxes 12-17)
  Numbers 1-892 (#24-25, #172, #184-209, #272, #326-329; #500, #506, #620 missing) of weekly newsletter produced by Lawrence Dennis, arranged chronologically.
- OPERATIONAL FILE, 1940-1974. (Box Boxes 18-22)
  Materials dealing with the production and distribution of Dennis' two newsletters, The Weekly Foreign Letter, and The Appeal to Reason. Includes correspondence, subscription lists, ledgers, and bank statements. Arranged by physical form.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1925-1974. (Box Boxes 23-24)
  Clippings, serial issues, pamphlets, reprints, leaflets, newsletters, other printed matter, press releases, speech transcripts, memoranda, legal briefs, notes and miscellany. Material relates broadly to contemporaneous political, economic, and social conditions in the United States, primarily domestic and foreign policy.
- NOTES, n.d. (Box Boxes 24-25)
  Notes assembled by Lawrence Dennis for use in his speeches and writings, not readily divisible by subject. Predominantly notecards, but several small notebooks are also included in this series.
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1915-1973
  - Biographical sketches, c. 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Printed, c. 1941-1946
    - Non-printed, n.d. Typescript.
  - Employment
    - U.S. Foreign service, 1921-1930. SEE ALSO: Subject file/U.S. Foreign relations/Nicaragua (Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1927-1930
      - Correspondence, 1921-1927. Also includes letter from Dennis offering his services in connection with WW II, 1941 Dec. 20.
    - J. & W. Seligman & Co., 1927 (Folder 3)
    - E.A. Pierce & Co., 1937-1939
      - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Folder 4)
      - Lectures (economic)
        - Clippings, 1937-1938 (Folder 5-6)
        - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Folder 7)
        - Notices and schedules, 1937
      - Non-printed material, 1938-1939
    - Independent commentator and writer (national and world affairs) SEE ALSO: Subject file/Isolationism and historical revisionism/Doenecke, Justus D.; Ribuffo, Leo P.
      - Clippings, 1935-1973 (Folder 8)
      - Lectures, 1934-1953
        - Correspondence, 1934-1953 (Folder 9)
        - Notices and schedules, 1934-1953 (Folder 10)
    - Interviews, 1957-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Libel trial, 1947 (Folder 12)
    - General. Includes complaint, partial summary of proceedings and correspondence
    - Clippings, 1947
  - Military training and service, 1915-1919 (Folder 13)
    - General, 1919
    - Correspondence, 1923. Also includes correspondence with Dennis, offering his services in connection with WW II, 1941-1942.
    - Documents, 1915-1919
  - Miscellany, 1937-1971. Includes property documents, divorce documents, tax materials, loan statements, and other personal miscellany. (Folder 14)
  - Stock certificates, 1929-1931; 1958 (Folder 15)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1930-1977
  - General, 1936-1975 (Box 1)
    - General, 1936-1974
      - Fragments
        - n.d. (Folder 16)
        - Dated, 1943-1972 (Folder 17)
      - Unidentified
        - n.d. (Folder 18)
        - Dated, 1936-1974 (Folder 19)
    - Academics, 1940-1975. Arranged alphabetically by individual. (Folder 20)
    - Media organizations, 1938-1971. Correspondence with newspapers, radio stations, other serial publications, etc., arranged alphabetically by organization. (Folder 21)
      - The Atlantic Monthly (Mildred Boie, Asst. Editor), 1938
      - The Commercial and Financial Chronicle (A. Wilfred May, Executive Editor), 1946
      - Human Events (Robert D. Kephart, Business Manager), 1965
      - Libertarian Analysis (Chuck Hamilton), 1971
      - The Nation (Caroline Whiting, Editorial Secretary, 1934; 1944)
      - The San Francisco News (John S. Piper, Financial Editor), 1940-1941
      - Zenith Radio Corporation (Ted Leitzell), 1952
    - Students, 1959-1972. Arranged alphabetically by individual. (Folder 22)
  - Alphabetical, 1930-1977 (Box 2)
    - General, 1936-1975
      - A-C, 1941-1973 (Folder 1)
      - D-G, 1935-1962 (Folder 2)
      - H-K, 1939-1975 (Folder 3)
      - L-N, 1940-1969 (Folder 4)
      - O-P, 1938-1974 (Folder 5)
      - R-S, 1938-1974 (Folder 6)
      - T-Z, 1936-1971 (Folder 7)
    - Individual, 1930-1977
      - Adamic, Louis, 1946-1951 (Folder 8)
      - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1930 (Folder 9)
      - Arnold, Thurman, 1940 (Folder 10)
      - Aronson, Moses J., 1941-1942 (Folder 11)
      - Baldwin, Roger N., 1940-1949 (Folder 12)
      - Barnes, Harry Elmer
        - 1946-1951 (Folder 13)
        - 1952-1956 (Folder 14)
        - 1957-1968 (Folder 15)
      - Barton, Bruce, 1944-1959 (Folder 16)
      - Bazinet, John L. (Father), 1940-1947 (Folder 17)
      - Beard, Charles A., 1946-1948 (Folder 18)
      - Berle, A.A., Jr., 1933-1946 (Folder 19)
      - Biddle, Francis J., 1942 (Folder 20)
      - Billstein, Alfred H., 1958-1972 (Folder 21)
      - Blodgett, John W., Jr. (Box 3)
        - 1941 (Folder 1)
        - 1942-1972 (Folder 2)
      - Bone, Homer T., 1949 (Folder 3)
      - Borchard, Edwin, 1945-1948 (Folder 4)
      - Brophy, Frank Cullen, 1941-1960 (Folder 5)
      - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1951 (Folder 6)
      - Budd, Arthur D. (Lt. Col.), 1943-1962 (Folder 7)
      - Buffett, Howard (and Mrs.), 1951-1962 (Folder 8)
      - Carto, Willis A., 1955-1956 (Folder 9)
      - Chamberlin, William H., 1943-1946 (Folder 10)
      - Clarke, Carter W. (General), n.d. (fragment) (Folder 11)
      - Cless, George H., Jr., 1942 (Folder 12)
      - Collins, Seward B., 1940 (Folder 13)
      - Costigan, Edward P., 1933 (Folder 14)
      - Craney, Ed, 1952-1971 Includes copies of letters to Senators Frank E. Moss and Gale W. McGee (Folder 15)
      - Cudahy, John, 1941-1942 (Folder 16)
      - Culbertson, Ely, 1942 (Folder 17)
      - Current, Richard N., 1948 (Folder 18)
      - Cutting, Bronson, 1933 (Folder 19)
      - Deatherage, George E., 1944-1956 (Folder 20)
      - DeTerra, Eleanor, 1951-1959 (Folder 21)
      - Doenecke, Justus D., 1970-1974 (Folder 22)
      - Dorizas, Michael (and Mrs.), 1940-1958 (Folder 23)
      - Dulles, John Foster (and Mrs.), 1940-1952 (Folder 24)
      - Eastman, Max, 1946 (Folder 25)
      - Eaton, Cyrus, 1961 (Folder 26)
      - Eccles, M.S., 1939 (Folder 27)
      - FitzSimons, Ellen French (Mrs. Paul), 1942 (Folder 28)
      - Fletcher, Joseph F. (Reverend), 1941 (Folder 29)
      - Garrett, Garet, c. 1952 (Folder 30)
      - Garrity, Devin A., 1954-1966 (Folder 31)
      - Goldsmith, Arthur J., 1939-1943 (Folder 32)
      - Goldwater, Barry, 1964 (Folder 33)
      - Green, James S., 1941-1958 (Folder 34)
      - Gross, Bertram M., 1971. (Folder 35)
      - Gund, George, 1966-1967 (Folder 36)
      - Harland, J.P., 1942 (Folder 37)
      - Hays, Arthur G., 1943-1953 (Folder 38)
      - Hewes, Clarence B. (Buzzy), 1942-1962. Includes excerpt from a letter to Clarence Hewes from the Duke of Windsor, 1956 July 5. (Folder 39)
      - Hodgdon, Dana A. and Dorothy, 1945-1967 (Folder 40)
      - Holt, Rush D., 1941 (Folder 41)
      - Hooker, De West, 1958-1975 (Folder 42)
      - Hoover, Herbert, 1942 (Folder 43)
      - Howe, Quincy, 1940 (Folder 44)
      - Hutton, Edward F., 1951 (Folder 45)
      - Johnson, Hiram W., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Johnson, Philip C., 1950-1958. Includes biographical clipping. (Folder 2)
      - Kendall, Willmoore, 1941-1947 (Folder 3)
      - Kennedy, Joseph P., 1951 (Folder 4)
      - Kern, Karl, 1942 (Folder 5)
      - Kipphan, Klaus, 1968-1969 (Folder 6)
      - Landon, Alf M., 1943-1949 (Folder 7)
      - Langer, William, 1957-1958 (Folder 8)
      - Laski, Harold J., 1936 (Folder 9)
      - LeBoutillier, Philip, 1940-1967 (Folder 10)
      - Libby, Frederick J., 1943-1967 (Folder 11)
      - Loughran, Clayton D., 1957-1974 (Folder 12)
      - Lovell, Malcolm R., 1956-1959 (Folder 13)
      - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1943 (Folder 14)
      - Lundeen, Ernest, 1940 (Folder 15)
      - Magoun, Francis P., Jr., 1946 (Folder 16)
      - Maguire, Russell, 1957 (Folder 17)
      - Mansfield, Mike, 1969 (Folder 18)
      - Marquand, Adelaide F.H. (Mrs. John P.), 1942-1949 (Folder 19)
      - Martin, James J.
        - 1958-1968 (Folder 20)
        - 1969-1972 (Folder 21)
      - McWilliams, Carey, 1955-1969 (Folder 22)
      - Miller, Clyde, 1940-1959 (Folder 23)
      - Moreno, Arthur Alphonse, 1938 (Folder 24)
      - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1969 (Folder 25)
      - Morley, Felix, 1943-1954 (Folder 26)
      - Morse, Charlotte I. (Mrs. Charles Hosmer Morse), 1947-1951 (Folder 27)
      - Morton, Sterling, 1946-1960 (Folder 28)
      - Moseley, George Van Horn (General), 1940-1949 (Folder 29)
      - Mullendore, W.C., 1952 (Folder 30)
      - Nickerson, Hoffman (and Mrs.), 1942-1975 (Folder 31)
      - Palmer, Paul, 1938-1969 (Folder 32)
      - Pearson, Drew, 1940 (Folder 33)
      - Peek, George N., 1942 (Folder 34)
      - Perry, Lewis, 1941 (Folder 35)
      - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1942 (Folder 36)
      - Pew, Joseph N., Jr., 1939 (Folder 37)
      - Pitkin, Walter B., 1951 (Folder 38)
      - Porzelt, Paul, 1960-1961 (Folder 39)
      - Prudden, R.F., n.d. Includes fragment from Prudden's Digest, 1958 Aug. 19. (Folder 40)
      - Ratcliffe, S.K., 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Regnery, Henry, 1957-1967 (Folder 2)
      - Rimanoczy, Richard S., 1959-1971 (Folder 3)
      - Robbins, Warren M., 1949-1967 (Folder 4)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1932 (Folder 5)
      - Rucker, Pierce C., 1947-1966 (Folder 6)
      - Sargent, Porter, 1942-1950 (Folder 7)
      - Schuman, Frederick L., 1940-1977. Includes letter from Frederick Schuman to Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr., 1960 Oct. 5. (Folder 8)
      - Shaw, George P., 1943 (Folder 9)
      - Shipstead, Henrik, 1943. SEE ALSO: Hewes, Clarence B. (Folder 10)
      - Simpson, A.D., 1937 (Folder 11)
      - Smith, Lawrence H., 1951-1953 (Folder 12)
      - Smith, Truman (Colonel), 1940-1957 (Folder 13)
      - Snow, John Howland, 1950-1976 (Folder 14)
      - Sokolsky, George E., 1943-1944 (Folder 15)
      - Stafford, Yone (Mrs. Bradley)
        - n.d. (Folder 16)
        - 1949-1977
      - St. George, Maximilian J., 1946-1950 (Folder 17)
      - Stoddard, Lothrop, 1946-1947 (Folder 18)
      - Stone, Harlan F., 1940 (Folder 19)
      - Strassburger, Ralph Beaver (and Mrs.), 1952-1959 (Folder 20)
      - Tansill, Charles C., 1950 (Folder 21)
      - Tead, Ordway, 1940-1959 (Folder 22)
      - Thomas, Norman, 1946-1956 (Folder 23)
      - Thompson, Dorothy, 1940-1967 (Folder 24)
      - Tinkham, George Holden, 1943-1952 (Folder 25)
      - Townsend, Francis Everett, 1940-1941 (Folder 26)
      - Townsend, Ralph, 1942-1972 (Folder 27)
      - Utley, Freda (Folder 28)
        - n.d.
        - 1969
      - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1943. SEE ALSO: Hewes, Clarence B. (Folder 29)
      - Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1944 (Folder 30)
      - Waldo, Richard, 1940 (Folder 31)
      - Wallace, DeWitt, 1941-1969 (Folder 32)
      - Walsh, J. Raymond, 1940-1949 (Folder 33)
      - Wedemeyer, A.C. (General), 1959-1973 (Folder 34)
      - Weir, Ernest T., 1951-1952 (Folder 35)
      - Wheeler, Burton K. (and Mrs.), 1952-1973 (Folder 36)
      - Wolfe, Henry F. (Reverend), 1942-1955 (Folder 37)
      - Wood, John T., 1952-1953 (Folder 38)
      - Wood, Robert E. (General), 1941-1953 (Folder 39)
      - Wormser, Rene A., 1954 (Folder 40)
      - Zapp, Manfred, 1956 (Folder 41)
      - Zipf, George Kingsley, 1941 (Folder 42)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1931-1975
  - Correspondence, 1934-1972 (Box 6)
    - General, 1934-1970
      - General. Includes invitations to submit articles, and inquiries from archival depositories. (Folder 1)
      - Responses to speech given on Town Hall of the Air 1938 April 7. Letters to Lawrence Dennis and carbon copies of his replies. (Folder 2)
    - Publishing companies, 1939-1972. Predominantly regarding the publication or reprinting of Dennis' works. (Folder 3)
      - Bantam Books, Inc., 1972
      - Devin-Adair Co. SEE: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Garrity, Devin A.
      - Greenwood Press, 1969-1971
      - Harper & Brothers/Harper & Row. Includes arrangements with AMS Press, Inc. SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Tead, Ordway
      - Henry Regnery Company. SEE: Correspondence/Alphabetical/Individual/Regnery, Henry
      - McGraw Hill Book Co., Inc., 1939; 1971-1972
      - Monticello Publishers, 1947
      - Ralph Myles Publisher, Inc., 1971. SEE ALSO: Correspondence/Martin, James J.
      - Roseman, Herbert C., 1970. SEE ALSO: Subject file/Isolationism and revisionism
      - St. Martin's Press, 1972
    - Requests to use Dennis' material in works by other authors, 1938-1971 (Folder 4)
      - Aaron, Daniel and Bendiner, Robert, 1968-1970. Material for The Strenuous Decade, Doubleday & Co., Inc., c. 1969
      - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1973
      - American Friends Service Committee, Spectrum, c. 1960
      - Bernard, L.L., 1938. Material for Social Control, MacMillan and Co.
      - Columbia University Teachers College, Bureau of Publications (Brunstetter, M.R., Editor), 1941. Material for Readings in the Foundations of Education, c. 1941.
      - Emenhiser, JeDon A. and Cazier, Stanford O., 1966. Material for Definition of American Democracy, c. 1967
      - Grob, Gerald and Beck, Robert N., 1962-1969. Material for American Ideas: Source Readings in the Intellectual History of the U.S., The Free Press, 1963, rev. 1970.
      - Polenberg, Richard, 1971. Material for Radicalism and Reform in the New Deal, Addison-Wesley Publishing Co., c. 1971
  - General speeches and writings, 1931-1970
    - Letters to editors, 1931-1970 (Folder 5)
      - General
      - Non-printed
        - c. 1931 May. Letter submitted by Dennis to the American Journal of International Law responding to criticism of Dennis' article Revolution, Recognition and Intervention(SEE: Speeches and writings/Published articles). Typescript, includes correspondence.
        - 1940 Dec. 18. Letter to New York Times, responding to article of same date(SEE: Subject file/Fascism and anti-fascism/U.S./Clippings). Carbon copy.
        - 1942 March 7. Letter to New York World-Telegram, responding to article of March 6. Includes two carbon copies, one of which carries editors marks, so it may, in fact, have been published.
        - 1942 April-May. Correspondence with Life Magazine, regarding article in issue of April 13. Also includes original inquiry addressed to Life, regarding the sources used for this article.
        - 1943 July 25. Letter to The Daily News, Jackson, Mississippi. Carbon copy.
        - 1948 March 29. Letter to Newsweek responding to article of same date (attached). Carbon copy.
        - 1960 Feb. 6. Letter to Newsweek, responding to article of Jan. 25 (attached). Carbon copy.
        - 1970 April. Statement to Playboy magazine, responding to May issue interview of William F. Buckley (attached). Includes correspondence.
      - Printed
        - 1951 Feb. 16. Berkshire Evening Eagle
        - 1951 Feb. 22. Berkshire Evening Eagle
        - 1956 April 11. Harvard Crimson
    - Miscellaneous texts, c. 1933-1955
      - Authorship established, 1934-1941 (Folder 6)
        - Peace Aims, 1941 Feb. 14. Memorandum for Eighth Fortune Round Table. Mimeographed copy.
        - A Planned Muddle Course, c. 1934. Typescript carbon copy. (Folder 7)
      - Authorship probable, but unconfirmed
        - Fragments, c. 1941-1945 (Folder 8)
        - Untitled, c. 1950-1953 (Folder 9)
        - Let's Save America from Permanent War and Inflation, c. 1950-1953 (Folder 10)
        - Memo on How to Combat the Infiltration of British Radicalism into this Country, c. 1933-1939 (Folder 11)
        - Review of Walter Lippmann, American Foreign Policy: Shield of the Republic, c. 1944 (Folder 12)
        - Too Much Use of Terms Like Business and Free Private Enterprise, c. 1933-1939 (Folder 13)
        - The War Powers Bill and Immigration, c. 1942 (Folder 14)
        - What Are We Fighting For? c. 1941-1945 (Folder 15)
        - The Yalta Agenda: Punishment for the Defeated; Spoils for Russia; U.N. Peace and Security Illisuions for the U.S. and Great Britain, c. 1955 (Folder 16)
    - Press releases, 1938-1941. Non-printed (Folder 17)
      - General. The Outlook for 1939, 1938 Dec. 21. For Associated Press (note in Dennis' hand). Carbon copy.
      - McClure Newspaper Syndicate. Mimeographed copies.
        - 1940 July 7. Interventionist with a Record.
        - 1940 July 27-28. The Third-term Strategy of Defense.
        - 1940 Aug. 10-11. The Strange Defense Campaign.
        - 1940 Aug. 24-25. Conscription and Revolution.
        - 1941 April 12-13. Ahead of the Headlines. Paul Palmer given as author, possibly in collaboration with Lawrence Dennis.
    - Speech transcripts, 1937-1952
      - Radio broadcasts, c. 1952. Untitled and otherwise unidentified. (Folder 18)
        - New American imperialism. Fragment of typescript.
        - New American imperialism, contd. Typescript.
        - Korea/Eisenhower campaign for Republican nomination. Typescript.
        - Eisenhower nomination/election of 1952. Typescript.
        - Fragment, Presidential election and Korea, c. 1952.
      - The Pattern of Legal Revolution and its Implications for the Traditional Doctrine of Free Thought and Free Speech, 1949 Dec. 2. Paper given at annual meeting of American Political Science Association. Mimeographed copy. (Folder 19)
      - Recovery, 1937 June 14. Address given at the Houston Club, Houston, Texas. Mimeographed copy. (Folder 20)
      - To Whom Belongs the Future? 1941 April 6. Address for symposium held by the Spinoza Institute, Brooklyn, New York. Typescript carbon copy. (Folder 21)
      - We're Preparing for the Worst Kind of War, c. 1950-1953. Typescript. (Folder 22)
  - Published articles, 1933-1959
    - The Balance of Impotence. Right, No. 45, 1959. Serial newsletter. (Folder 23)
    - Can Our Banks Be Made Safe? The Nation, 1933 March 15. Serial issue. (Folder 24)
    - Economic Nationalism: Is It to Be Opposed or Guided? The Town Crier, c. 1935. Clipping. (Folder 25)
    - Full Recovery or Stagnation? Today's Challenge, 1939 Aug.-Sept. Serial issue. (Folder 26)
    - Political Anti-Semitism in a Fascist America is Unthinkable, Says Advocate of Strong Ruler. Emanu-El-Jewish Journal, 1934 Oct. 26. Reprint. (Folder 27)
    - Review of Frederick L. Schuman, The Commonwealth of Man. The Berkshire Evening Eagle, 1952 Dec. 6. Clipping. (Folder 28)
    - Revolution, Recognition and Intervention. Foreign Affairs, 1931 January. Reprint. (Folder 29)
    - The Third Great Boom Since 1914, c. 1937. Pamphlet sponsored by E.A. Pierce & Co. (Folder 30)
  - Books, 1940-1969 (Box 7)
    - Dynamics of War and Revolution, 1940
      - Arrangements for publication
        - Correspondence and price quotations, 1940-1942 (Folder 1)
        - Invoices and shipping receipts, 1940-1942 (Folder 2)
      - Complimentary copy acknowledgements. Copies were sent by Dennis to university libraries all over the country.
        - Cards. Unsorted (Folder 3)
        - Correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by institution (Folder 4-5)
      - Orders, 1940-1942
        - General (Folder 6-7)
        - Correspondence
      - Reviewers, 1940-1941 (Folder 8)
        - General
        - Correspondence
    - A Trial on Trial, 1946
      - General, 1969 (Folder 9)
      - Promotional material, 1946
      - Reviews, 1946-1947
        - General. Publication announcements in journals.
        - American Bar Association Journal, 1946 Oct.
        - Chicago Daily Law Bulletin, 1946 Dec. 18
        - Texas Law Review, 1947 April
    - Unpublished, fragmentary manuscripts, c. 1950's
      - Untitled (#1): Refers to the Nuremberg pattern in international law: effect on American interests and general peace during Cold War Era, c. 1952.
        - Introduction., Three fragments. Typescript (Folder 10)
        - Chapter 1. Selling Germans Rearmament requires Selling Americans the End of Nuremberg. Typescript (Folder 11)
        - Nuremberg-Made International Criminal Law Against Individuals Lacks Validity, Utility and it Threatens U.S. National Interest and World Peace. Typescript carbon copy (Folder 12)
        - The Semantic or Meaning Problem of International Criminal Law. Includes footnote. Typescript carbon copy (Folder 13)
        - Consent, not Coercion or Punishment the path to World Unity and a World Legal Order. Typescript carbon copy (Folder 14)
        - Untitled. Four chapters. Typescript carbon copies (Folder 15)
      - Untitled (#2): Refers to patterns of error in analysis of U.S.-international relations, c. 1954
        - A New Look: Error, not Guilt. Includes four draft fragments: two typescript originals; two carbon copies. (Folder 16-17)
        - The Nemesis of the West: Miscalculations, not False Values., Two drafts: one typescript original; one carbon copy (Folder 18)